

COLLEGE PARK MD, USA

🛘 +1 2408257455 | 🔀 bansal01@umd.edu | 🄏 arpitbansal297.github.io | 🖸 github.com/arpitbansal297

Research Interests ____

My broad research interest lies in understanding and improving the way Deep Neural Networks train and perform inference. My research work ranges from making neural networks perform logical extrapolation with more compute time to watermarking neural networks to understanding neural networks behaviors. Currently I am working on understanding diffusion models and adopting them to solve different AI tasks.

Education

University of Maryland, College Park

PHD IN COMPUTER SCIENCE (4.0/4.0)

- Advisor: Prof. Tom Goldstein
- Dean's Fellowship

Indian Institute of Technology, Kharagpur

BACHELORS + MASTERS IN ELECTRICAL ENGINEERING

- Minor in Computer Science
- Advisor: Prof. Rajiv Ranjan Sahay

College Park Jan 2021 - present

Kharagpur, India Aug 2014 - May 2019

Industry Experience _____

July 2019 - Dec 2020 Software Developer, Visa Incorporated, India

May 2018 - July 2018 Software Developer Intern, Visa Incorporated, India
May 2017 - July 2017 Software Developer Intern, Fission Labs, India

Publications

Can You Learn the Same Model Twice? Investigating Reproducibility and Double Descent from the Decision Boundary Perspective

G. Somepalli, L. Fowl, **A. Bansal**, P. Yeh Chiang, Y. Dar, R. Baraniuk, M.GoldBlum, T. Goldstein *Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR - Oral) 2022*

Certified Neural Network Watermarks with Randomized Smoothing

A. Bansal, P. Yeh Chiang, M. Curry, R. Jain, C. Wigington, V. Manjunatha, J. P Dickerson, T. Goldstein *International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML - Spotlight) 2022*

Preprints _____

A. Bansal, M. Goldblum, V. Cherepanova, A. Schwarzschild, C Bayan Bruss, T. Goldstein, *MetaBalance: High-Performance Neural Networks for Class-Imbalanced Data*

A. Bansal, A. Schwarzschild, E. Borgnia, Z. Emam, F. Huang, M. Goldblum, T. Goldstein, *Thinking Deeper With Recurrent Networks: Logical Extrapolation Without Overthinking*

A. Schwarzschild, E. Borgnia, A. Gupta, **A. Bansal**, Z. Emam, F. Huang, M. Goldblum, T. Goldstein, *Datasets for studying generalization from easy to hard examples*

L. Fowl, P. yeh Chiang, M. Goldblum, J. Geiping, **A. Bansal**, W. Czaja, T. Goldstein, *Preventing unauthorized use of proprietary data: Poisoning for secure dataset release*

A. Bansal, S. Jonna, R. R Sahay, Pag-net: Progressive attention guided depth super-resolution network

Teaching Experience _____

Fall 2021 **Control Systems**, Teaching Assistant Spring 2021 **Operating Systems**, Teaching Assistant

University of Maryland, College Park University of Maryland, College Park

Relevant Course-work _____

Machine Learning

 $Information \ Retrieval \ (IIT), \ Machine \ Learning \ (IIT), \ Speech \ and \ NLP \ (IIT), \ Deep \ Learning \ (IIT), \ Speech \ and \ NLP \ (IIT), \ Speech \ and \ and \ Speech \ and \$

(UMD) Algorithms in Machine Learning (UMD)

Signal Processing

Digital Signal Processing (IIT), Statistical Signal Processing (IIT), Probability and Stochastic Processes (IIT), Random Processes (UMD), Information Theory (UMD), Numerical Analysis I (UMD), Advanced Numerical Optimization (UMD)